A Guide to the G. Vere Tyler Papers, 1915-1925
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
G. Vere Tyler Papers 1915-1925
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10950
This collection consists of ca. 200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Phillip W. Rhodes, Acting Director, Jones Memorial Library, Lynchburg, Virginia, on April 25, 1990.
Scope and Content Information
There are ca. 200 items, 1915-1925, of essayist, journalist, novelist and playwright G. Vere Tyler of Richmond, Virginia. Included are typescripts of the plays Alma, the Bootlegger and The Crucifix, the latter being a revised version of the first with heavy annotations; an autograph manuscript, with typed revisions, of the novel His First Want; typescripts for five short plays: Belgium Every Day, Getting a Husband, Old Black Joe, One of the Boys, and A Tiny Gibralter; brief writings including articles, essays, and play synopses--many concerning women; and unidentified partial manuscripts. There are also three newspaper clippings, 1916, about Mrs. Tyler's writing career.
Contents List
- Manuscripts (Box 1)
  - Plays and Novels (Box 1)
    - Alma, the Bootlegger(also The Crucifix), a play in three acts 1925 (Box 1)
    - The Crucifix(originally Alma, the Bootlegger), a play in three acts 1925 (Box 1)
    - His First Want, a novel [1915] (Box 1)
    - Plays 1916-1918 (Box 1)
  - Other Manuscripts (Box 1)
    - Brief Writings n.d. (Box 1)
    - Unidentified Incomplete Manuscripts n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
- Printed Material re G. Vere Tyler 1916 (Box 1)